Guide to the Van Ness-Philip Family Papers 1711-1963 (bulk 1711-1945) MS 653
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV: John Van Ness Philip (d. 1862)
  - Correspondence, 1854 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1856-1857 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1858 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, undated, circa 1850 Jan.-1860 Jun. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, circa 1850 Jul.-1860 Dec. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1859 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: receipt, 1860 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: newspaper clipping, 1861 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1862 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, calling cards, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: poems, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Misc. portraits, address and oration, memorial address, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Boats signals: U. S. Frigate Columbia, 1843 (Box 20, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal, 1839 Aug.-1839 Oct. (Box 20, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal, undated (Box 20, Folder unknown container)
  - Writings, undated (Box 20, Folder unknown container)
  - Travel journal, Exercise of Great Guns, undated (Box 20, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal of John Van Ness Philip aboard U. S. Recog. Ship Columbus and U. S. Frigate Columbia, 1841-1842 (Box 20, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal of John Van Ness Philip, 1842-1843 (Box 20, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal of John Van Ness Philip aboard U. S. S. Columbia, 1843 (Box 20, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal, notes, and calculations of John Van Ness Philip, 1844-1845 (Box 20, Folder unknown container)
  - Diary, 1849 Jun.-1849 Oct. (Box 21, Folder unknown container)
  - Log book, 1845-1846 (Box 21, Folder unknown container)
- Series V: William Henry Philip
  This series contains correspondence and papers (ca.1840's-1881), of his years at Lenox Academy and Williams College, travels in Europe, service in the Civil War, candidacy for Congress, and life as a lawyer and businessman in Washington, D.C.
  - Correspondence, 1841-1844 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1845 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1846 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1847 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1847 Jul.-1847 Dec. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1848 Jan.-1848 Jun. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1848 Jul.-1848 Dec. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1849 Jan.-1849 Jun. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1849 Jul.-1849 Dec. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Williams College (1842-1879), Lenox Academy, circa 1840-1850 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Writings, circa 1830-1850 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Writings, circa 1840-1850 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Writings, circa 1840-1850 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1850 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1851 Jan.-1851 Jun. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1851 Jul.-1851 Dec. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1852 Jan.-1852 Jun. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1852 Jul.-1852 Dec. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1853 Jan.-1853 Jun. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1853 Jul.-1853 Dec. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Letters of recommendation for Secretary of Legation, 1853 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Letters of introduction, 1853-1854 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1854 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1855 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Speech: Democratic speech delivered in Claverack, 1856 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1856 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1857 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1858 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1859 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Philmont Factory correspondence, circa 1850-1870 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Philmont Factory accounts, undated, circa 1850-1880 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - U. S. Army recommendations for Lt. Colonel, 1861-1863 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - U. S. Army letters of recommendation, undated, 1869-1876 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Commissions, 1861 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, poem, undated, circa 1860-1870 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1860 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1861 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1862 Jan.-1862 Jun. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1862 Jul.-1862 Dec. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1863 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1864 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1865 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1867 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1869 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with currency, [1860-1870] (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Speeches, notes for Congressional canvas, 1870 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1870 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1871 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - The Experience of the Lambert Tree...during the Great Chicago Fire, 1871 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Titusville, PA from M. H. Philip, 1871-1872 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1872 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1873 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Titusville from M. H. Philip, 1873 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1874 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Minnesota letters from M. H. Philips, 1874 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1875 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1876 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1877 Jan.-1877 Jul. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Laurel Hill Association for Claverack Village, circa 1870-1880 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1877 Aug.-1877 Sep. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1878 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1879 Jan.-1879 Apr. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1879 May-1879 Jul. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1879 Aug.-1879 Sep. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1879 Oct.-1879 Nov. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1879 Dec. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Jan. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Feb. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Mar. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Apr. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1880 May (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Jun. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Jul.-1880 Dec. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1881 Jan.-1881 Dec. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence re: interring of W. H. Philip, biographical information, 1882 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Misc. writings, undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Receipts, deeds, unsorted business papers, circa 1869-1879 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Receipts, deeds, unsorted business papers, circa 1849-1893 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Receipts, deeds, unsorted business papers, circa 1849-1880 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Receipts, deeds, unsorted business papers, circa 1850-1876 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Receipts, deeds, unsorted business papers, circa 1869-1879 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Misc: receipts,/indentures, accounts, song, 1828-1858 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Misc: receipts, pass, insurance, 1860-1869 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Misc: receipts, indentures, 1870-1878 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Misc. receipts, 1879 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Misc: receipts, tax assessments, 1880-1888 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Misc: photographs, undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Misc: Receipts, accounts, undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Misc: calling cards and invitations, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Misc: envelopes, undated (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Misc: poems, undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Misc: printed material, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Misc: newspaper clippings, circa 1880 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Columbia Turnpike: petition and copy of charter, undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Misc., 1894 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Memo and receipt book, undated (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - William H. Philip's memo book of personal expenses, undated (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Notes on European history, undated (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Receipt book, circa 1853-1869 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Private journal of William H., Philip: Italy, France, Germany, 1854 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Claverack Falls Summer School, accounts, 1850-1887 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Cash book, 1868-1871 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Appointment and receipt book, 1878 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - French phrase book, undated (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Private journal during trip to Paris, 1853 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Receipt book, 1873 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Notebook on class lectures, undated (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Bank of Kinderhook account book of William Henry Philip, 1850 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Receipt book, circa 1894 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Accounts book, 1887-1888 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Bank of Washington account book of William H. Philip, 1872-1874 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Bank of Washington account book of William H. Philip, 1874-1876 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Bank of Washington account book of William H. Philip, 1870-1878 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Expenses book of William H. Philip, 1869-1870 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Accounts book of the Patriot Newspaper Association, 1871-1873 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Copy of lease John Peter Van Ness and Will G. Williams, William H. Philip rents, circa 1868 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Tenants accounts, circa 1868-1869 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Accounts book, circa 1863 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Ledger, 1871-1880 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Memo book kept on Paris trip, circa 1851 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Notebook, circa 1881-1882 (Box 33, Folder unknown container)
  - Analyses of Blair's lectures, 1844 (Box 34, Folder unknown container)
  - Memo book of William Henry Philip, 1870-1873 (Box 34, Folder unknown container)
  - Accounts book, 1847-1873 (Box 34, Folder unknown container)
  - Notebook of original writings, circa 1843-1846 (Box 34, Folder unknown container)
  - Ledger, 1880-1881 (Box 34, Folder unknown container)
  - Ledger, 1872-1880 (Box 34, Folder unknown container)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings concerning William H. Philip's electoral campaign, circa 1870 (Box 34, Folder unknown container)
  - Memo book, circa 1853 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Memo book: trip to Europe, undated (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Appointment book, circa 1860 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Passport, 1854 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Travel journal, circa 1854 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Ledger, circa 1852-1855 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Receipt book, circa 1842-1845 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal, receipt book, 1877-1879 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - "Talavera" Farm book no. 1, 1870-1871 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - "Talavera" Farm book no. 2, 1872-1873 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - "Talavera" Farm book no. 3, 1873-1874 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Talavera Farm book, 1874-1876 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Talavera Farm book, 1878-1879 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Leroy Van Hoesen farmer account book no. 4, 1874-1875 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Leroy Van Hoesen farmer account book, 1877-1878 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Private journal of William Henry Philip, 1853-1854 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Class album, circa 1839-1850 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Private journal of William Henry Philip, vol. 3, circa 1854 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Rent book, 1866-1867 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Account book, circa 1864-1868 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal, 1852 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Survey of land, description, misc., undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: deed, 1847-1898 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Misc. correspondence, maps, printed material, undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
- Series VI: Eliza W. Philip
  Series VI is dedicated to Eliza Worthington Philip's correspondence and papers (ca. 1860's-1896), covering her early schooling, travels in Europe, marriage in 1864 to William Henry Philip, family life at Talavera in Claverack, Columbia County, New York, and later life in Washington, D.C. and Europe.
  - Correspondence, circa 1850-1860 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, circa 1860-1870 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1870 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1871 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1872 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1873 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1875 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1876 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1877 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1878 Jan.-1878 Aug. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1878 Sep.-1878 Dec. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1879 Jan. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1879 Feb. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1879 Mar. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1879 Apr. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1879 May (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1879 Jun. (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1879 Jul.-1879 Aug. (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1879 Sep.-1879 Dec. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Jan.-1880 Feb. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Mar.-1880 Apr. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1880 May-1880 Jun. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Jul.-1880 Aug. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Sep.-1880 Dec. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1881 Jan.-1881 Feb. (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1881 Mar.-1881 Apr. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1881 May (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1881 Jun.-1881 Jul. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1881 Aug.-1881 Dec. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Will, etc., 1881 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1882 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1883 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1884 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1885 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1886 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1887 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1888 Jan.-1888 Aug. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1888 Sep.-1888 Dec. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1889 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, undated, [1880-1890] (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1891 Jan.-1891 Sep. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1891 Oct.-1891 Dec. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1892 Jan.-1892 Jun. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1892 Jul.-1892 Dec. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1893 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1894 Jan.-1894 Jul. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1894 Aug.-1894 Dec. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1895 Jan.-1895 Jun. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1895 Jul.-1895 Dec. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Frances Cleveland, circa 1890-1900 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, undated, circa 1890-1900 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, invitations, undated (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, invitations, undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, invitations, undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, invitations, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Misc: engraving plate, poems, indenture, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, printed material, undated (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous: bills and receipts, undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous: bills and receipts, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous: printed invitations, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous: printed invitations, calling cards, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous: printed invitations, calling cards, undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous: envelopes, undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous: envelopes, undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Memo book, undated (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Notepad, undated (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - General account book, 1896 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Receipt book, circa 1869-1882 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Party planning notes, undated (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Cash book, receipts, notes, 1869-1896 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Notebook, circa 1867-1888 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Farmers National Bank account book, 1881-1884 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Address book, undated (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal, 1889 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Invitations book, 1895-1896 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Farmer's and Mechanics National Bank account book, circa 1882-1887 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Farmer's and Mechanics National Bank account book, circa 1887 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal, 1894 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Visiting list, circa 1892-1896 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Notebook, circa 1867-1871 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Scrapbook, notes, circa 1865-1875 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Visitor book, 1867-1872 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Notebook, circa 1864-1865 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Notebook, circa 1879 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Wallet, 1890-1894 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Pocket diary of Lilah Worthington, circa 1863-1864 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
  - Check book, 1889 (Box 47, Folder unknown container)
- Series VII: John Van Ness Philip (d. 1949)
  This series, circa 1870's-1949, covers John Van Ness Philip's years at Princeton, service in the Spanish-American War, life as a lawyer and social figure in Washington, D.C., travels in Europe, and involvement in Columbia County politics.
  - Correspondence, circa 1870-1879 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, circa 1880-1889 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Princeton certificates, 1885-1888 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1880-1881 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1882 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1883-1885 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1886 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1887 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1888 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1889 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Misc. invitations, circa 1880-1899 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1891 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1892 Jan.-1892 Jun. (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1892 Jul.-1892 Dec. (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1893 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1894 Jan.-1894 Jun. (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1894 Jul.-1894 Dec. (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1895 Jan.-1895 Jun. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1895 Jul.-1895 Dec. (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1896 Jan.-1896 Dec. (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: condolences, 1896 Oct.-1896 Nov. (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: condolences, 1896 Nov. (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Papers: death of Eliza W. Philip, 1896 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Convention badges, 1896 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1897 Jan.-1897 Jul. (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1897 Aug.-1897 Dec. (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Business correspondence, 1897 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1898 Jan.-1898 Aug. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1898 Sep.-1898 Dec. (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1899 Jan.-1899 May (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1899 Sep.-1899 Dec. (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1900 Jan.-1900 Apr. (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1900 May-1900 Jul. (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1900 Aug.-1900 Dec. (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1901 Jan.-1901 Jun. (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1901 Sep.-1901 Dec. (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Business correspondence, 1895 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Business correspondence, 1896 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Business correspondence, undated, 1897 Jan.-1897 Feb. (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Business correspondence, 1987 Mar.-1897 Apr. (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Business correspondence, 1897 May-1897 Jun. (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Business correspondence, 1897 Jul.-1897 Aug. (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Business correspondence, 1897 Sep.-1897 Dec. (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Business correspondence, 1898 Jan.-1898 Jun. (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1902 Jan.-1902 Apr. (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1902 Jul.-1902 Dec. (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Louisiana Purchase Exposition, 1903 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1905 Jan.-1905 Apr. (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1905 May-1905 Oct. (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1906-1907 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1908 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, some photos, 1909 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1910 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1911 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1912 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1913 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1914 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1921-1928 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Business correspondence, undated, 1906-1922 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Business correspondence, undated, 1928-1931 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1933 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Political correspondence, undated, 1936-1938 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Columbian News (forms), circa 1930-1939 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Columbian News: shareholders, capital expenses, circa 1930-1939 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Columbian News: correspondence, 1936-1938 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - China treaty: correspondence and papers, 1935 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - China treaty: papers, 1936 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - China treaty: printed materials, 1936 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Pan American Highway: correspondence, papers, circa 1940-1959 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Democratic Union, A-L, 1933 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Democratic Union, M-L, 1933 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence papers: Democratic Union, circa 1930-1939 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Misc: Democratic Union, circa 1930-1939 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Ledger, circa 1934-1935 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Receipt book, circa 1934 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Check book, 1934 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Deposit slip book, 1933 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Farmer's National Bank account book, 1933-1934 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, undated (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Invitations, undated (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (recipes), undated (Box 56, Folder 6)